

CONTACT

- **** 06 18 23 22 02
- ✓ sothea.has@lpsm.paris
- Paris, France
- https://hassothea.github.io/

EDUCATION

2018 - 2022 SORBONNE UNIVERSITÉ

PhD in Applied Mathematics

2018

UNIVERSITÉ PARIS DIDEROT

• Mater's degree of Data Science

ENSIIE

• Engineer of Applied Mathematics

2015

ROYAL UNIVERSITY OF PHNOM PENH, CAMBODIA

• Bachelor's degree in mathematics

SKILLS

- Applied machine learning (ML)
- Theoretical ML and Statistics
- Data analysis and modeling
- ML for climate science
- Python, PyTorch, R, C++, ...

LANGUAGES

- Khmer (mother tongue)
- English (fluent)
- French (conversational)

HAS SOTHEA

PHD IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS

PROFILE

I am currently a postdoctoral researcher in applied Machine Learning (ML) in climate science at Laboratoire de Météorologie Dynamique (LMD) of École Normale Supérieure (ENS), France. My area of expertise is theoretical/applied ML, Statistics, and Data Science. I have been very interested in data and tasks involving using ML tools.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CNRS/LPSM - ENS/LMD - École polytechnique 2022 - PRESENT Postdoctoral researcher

- Applied ML in reconstructing a time series of Gravity Wave Momentum Fluxes (GWMF)
- Extracting import features for reconstruction and insights
- Building a Python library for various aggregation methods

Teaching at Université Paris Cité 2019 - 2024 Teaching assistant for 1st and 2nd year Master students

- Data Analysis with R and Rstudio
- Data Mining with R and Rstudio
- Exploratory Data Analysis with R and Rstudio
- Algorithm and Programming with Python
- Big Data Technologies with Python and Spark
- Statistical Inference and Data Modeling

LPSM - Université Paris Cité PhD research and projects

2018 - 2022

- Theoretical studies of consensual aggregation method in ML
- · Combining supervised and unsupervised ML for data modeling
- Energy modeling (wind turbine & air compression machine)
- Applied ML in physical quantity modeling (pitch angle diffusion)

PUBLICATION

- 2024, Estimating balloon-observed gravity wave momentum fluxes using ML & input from ERA5. Published in JGR-Atmosphere.
- **2023**, Gradient COBRA: A kernel-based consensual aggregation for regression. *Published in Journal of Data Science, Statistics and Visualization.*
- **2022**, A consensual aggregation of randomly projected high-dimensional features of predictions. *Available in HAL*.
- 2022, Machine learning methods applied to the global modeling of eventdriven pitch angle diffusion coefficients during high-speed streams. Published in Frontiers Physics.
- **2021**, KFC: A clusterwise supervised learning procedure based on aggregation of distances. *Published in Journal of Statistical Computation and Simulation.*